{"tossups": [{}, {"question": "The EPA recently blocked this politician\u2019s attempt to divert half a billion dollars from a clean-water fund to road construction. This man reneged on a 2011 promise to veto gerrymandered lines for a State Senate lead by Dean Skelos. This secretary of HUD under Bill Clinton abruptly shut down the anti-corruption Moreland Commission in 2014. His re-election campaign featured contentious negotiations for the endorsement of the Working Families Party and a primary challenge by law professor Zephyr Teachout. A new Tappan Zee Bridge is being championed by, for the point, what current Governor of New York?", "answer": "<b><u>A</u></b>ndrew <b><u>Cuomo</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "CW"}, {"question": "A poem about this leader said he would \u201cdo nothing by halves which can be done by quarters.\u201d For his country\u2019s safety, this man created the Permanent Joint Board of Defence and signed the Ogdensburg Agreement. He set up the Rowell-Sirois Commission on federal-provincial relations. This man was elected to his third ministry by saying that it was him \u201cor chaos,\u201d after a constitutional crisis in which he was replaced with his rival Arthur Meighen by Governor General Julian Byng. For the point, name this Liberal, Canada\u2019s longest serving prime minister.", "answer": "William Lyon Mackenzie <b><u>King</u></b> [do not accept \u201cWilliam Lyon Mackenzie\u201d]  {III}", "metadata": "MW/PL"}, {"question": "For much of the 1500s, this kingdom was ruled by the Foix and Albret families. A Constable of France named Charles de la Cerda was assassinated on the orders of one of this kingdom\u2019s rulers named Charles the Bad. This kingdom\u2019s ruler Sancho VII successfully led the right wing at the Battle of Las Navas de Tolosa. Richard the Lionheart\u2019s wife Berengaria was a princess from this kingdom, whose most famous ruler was made king of France after declaring that \u201cParis is well worth a mass.\u201d For the point, name this original home of France\u2019s Henry IV, a kingdom in the Pyrenees with capital at Pamplona.", "answer": "Kingdom of <b><u>Navarre</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "SL"}, {"question": "This song\u2019s producer Charlie Greene attempted to obscure a slang term for the police with a cymbal crash.This song was inspired by the reaction to the closing of the Pandora\u2019s Box. It declares that it was \u201ca field day for the heat,\u201d and describes \u201cyoung people\u201d with signs that \u201cmostly say, \u2018hooray for our side\u2019.\u201d This song, which was written in response to the Sunset Strip riots of 1966, was titled after an offhand remark made by its writer, Stephen Stills. \u201cStop, children, what\u2019s that sound, everybody look what\u2019s going down\u201d declares the chorus of, for the point, what protest song by Buffalo Springfield?", "answer": "<b><u>\u201cFor What It\u2019s Worth\u201d</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "CW"}, {"question": "The second book titled for this group recounts how one of its leaders died after the elephant he stabbed from beneath fell on him. A book named for this group ends with the death of Nicanor. From Aristobulus I to Aristobulus III, a line of kings descended from them also held the office of high priest.The founder of this group lived in the village of Modi\u2019in. The Hasmonean dynasty was founded by this group, which revolted against the Seleucid ruler Antiochus IV. Their name may be Aramaic for \u201chammer.\u201d For the point, Judah was the leader and namesake of what rebels who inspired Hanukkah?", "answer": "<b><u>Maccabee</u></b>s [or <b><u>Makabi</u></b>m; accept <b><u>2</u></b>nd book of <b><u>Maccabees</u></b>; accept <b><u>Hasmonean</u></b>s or <b><u>Hashmona</u></b>im before \u201cHasmonean\u201d]  {III}", "metadata": "SH"}, {"question": "While in Flanders, this man became \u201cGovernor of the English Nation of Merchant Adventurers.\u201dThis man claimed he was born in Weald, Kent in his first printed work, a translation of Raoul Lefevre\u2019s romance about the history of Troy. This man\u2019s <em>The Book of the</em> <em>Knight in the Tower</em>, was one of the first English texts to contain passages from the Bible. He was also responsible for spreading the legend of King Arthur by printing a text by Thomas Malory. For the point, name this 15th century merchant, who introduced the printing press to England.", "answer": "William <b><u>Caxton</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "Ike"}, {"question": "William Rehnquist cited this essay in opposition to over-broad use of judicial review in his opinion in Furman v. Georgia. Decades before Dorr's Rebellion, it claimed that \"some power altogether independent of the people\" would quickly take over Rhode Island if that state split off from the rest of the Union. It asks rhetorically if government is \"but the greatest of reflections on human nature\" before claiming that \"If men were angels, no government would be necessary.\" This essay from an 85-part collection argues for a government structured so \"Ambition [is] made to counteract ambition.\" For the point, name this Federalist paper which coined the term \"checks and balances.\"", "answer": "<em><b><u>Federalist</u></b></em> Paper No. <b><u>51</u></b> [or \"The <b><u>Structure of the Government Must Furnish the</u></b> <b><u>Proper Checks and Balances Between the Different Departments</u></b>\"until \"checks\"; prompt on <em><b><u>Federalist</u></b> Papers</em>]  {III}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "A science historian with this surname documented the use of nuclear propulsion in his book Project Orion. It\u2019s not Butler, but George, a science historian with this surname, wrote about the evolution of intelligence in his 1997 book <em>Darwin Among the Machines</em>. An astronomer with this surname suggested that Type II Kardashev civilizations could be found via a method proposed in his paper \u201cSearch for Artificial Stellar Sources of Infrared Radiation.\u201d For the point, what is the last name of the theoretical astronomer who postulated the existence of namesake spheres that surround stars to harvest their energy?", "answer": "<b><u>Dyson</u></b> [or George <b><u>Dyson</u></b> or Freeman <b><u>Dyson</u></b>]  {III}", "metadata": "Ike"}, {"question": "The legendary king Codrus tricked an army of these people into killing him in order to save his city. An alliance of cities founded by this group in Asia Minor was called the hexapolis. The appearance of this group is connected to the mythical return of the children of Heracles. This group may have caused the \"Dark Ages\" by attacking a civilization that used the Linear B script. This group names an order of column that contrasts with the Ionic and the Corinthian. For the point, name this ethnic group that is thought to have destroyed the Mycenaean culture by invading Greece.", "answer": "<b><u>Dorian</u></b>s [or <b><u>Doric</u></b> people; prompt on \"Greeks\", \"Hellenic people\", or similiar answers]  {III}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "This man complained that he felt like an independent merchant going up against a chain store during the primaries for one election. In a famous speech, this man told \u201cthose who say that we are rushing this issue of civil rights\u201d that in fact \u201cwe are 172 years too late!\u201d This lead author, with Everett Dirksen, of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 earned the nickname \u201cThe Happy Warrior\u201d for his championing of liberal causes. With Ed Muskie, this former mayor of Minneapolis emerged victorious from a fiercely-protested nominating convention in Chicago. For the point, name this Vice President of Lyndon Johnson, who ran unsuccessfully as a Democrat in the 1968 election.", "answer": "Hubert <b><u>Humphrey</u></b> [or Hubert Horatio <b><u>Humphrey</u></b> Jr.]  {III}", "metadata": "AG"}, {"question": "This was the first major empire to use the town of Walata as a hub of commerce. Members of this \"pagan\" empire threw dust on their heads as its ruler went by, according to the Islamic geographer al-Bakri. This empire, in which a large serpent called the Bida was worshipped, besieged and absorbed Audaghost. It faded after the Almoravids attacked its largest city, Kumbi Saleh. The monarch of this empire, whose title was also this empire's name, claimed an exclusive monopoly on all gold pieces larger than dust. For the point, name this empire which dominated the West African salt-gold trade before Mali.", "answer": "<b><u>Ghana</u></b> empire [or <b><u>Wagadou</u></b>gu]  {III}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "An itinerary of places around this geographical feature by Arrian of Nicomedia mentioned Ionopolis and Trapezus. Paphlagonia was a region along the southern edge of this body of water, at which Xenophon's Ten Thousand exclaimed \"Thalassa! Thalassa!\" Chersonesus was a colony on this body of water, which the Greeks called Pontus Euxinus. Chalcedon processed the grain trade from this body of water, which was grown in the Azov region. For the point, name this sea settled by some Greeks, who sailed northeast through the Bosporus by Byzantium to reach it.", "answer": "<b><u>Black</u></b> Sea [or Pontus <b><u>Euxinus</u></b> before mention; or <b><u>Euxine</u></b> Sea before \"Euxinus\"]  {III}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "A Richard Russell chaired committee said this decision was a \"shock to national pride.\" After this decision was made, Robert Taft said the country \"is led by a fool who is surrounded by knaves.\" It was defended by a man using, for the first time, the phrase \"the wrong war, at the wrong place, and the wrong time.\" This decision resulted in the promotion of Matthew Ridgway. A few days after this decision was made, the man it affected gave the \"Old Soldiers Never Die\" speech in front of Congress. For the point, name this April 1951 decision in which President Truman relieved a General of the Army fighting in the Korean War.", "answer": "Harry Truman\u2019s <b><u>relief</u></b> of Douglas <b><u>MacArthur</u></b> [accept words like <b><u>firing</u></b> or <b><u>dismissal</u> </b>or other synonyms in place of \u201crelief\u201d]  {III}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "This director\u2019s comedy about a panic breaking out in Los Angeles after Pearl Harbor is titled for the year 1941. In one of this director's movies, Anthony Hopkins plays John Quincy Adams and Djimon Hounsou plays Joseph Cinque. Daniel Craig plays a South African who volunteers to help assassinate the perpetrators of the 1972 Olympics massacre in another of his films. This director of <em>Amistad</em> and <em>Munich</em> cast Ralph Fiennes as a Nazi war criminal and Daniel Day Lewis as a United States president in other films. For the point, name this director of <em>Schindler\u2019s List</em> and <em>Lincoln</em>.", "answer": "Steven <b><u>Spielberg</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "EA"}, {"question": "This person\u2019s secretary, Fabre d\u2019Eglantine, was implicated for trying to scam money using the East India Company. This person produced a newspaper with his friend, Camille Desmoulins, and proclaimed \u201cWe need audacity, and yet more audacity, and always audacity.\u201d He was held responsible by his enemies for the September Massacres, and this President of the Cordeliers club told the crowd that his only regret was that he was \u201cgoing before that rat Robespierre.\u201d For the point, name this first president of the Committee of Public Safety who was later guillotined for his opposition to the Reign of Terror.", "answer": "Georges Jacques <b><u>Danton</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "JZ"}, {"question": "This event inspired Julia Wolfe\u2019s <em>Big Beautiful Dark and Scary</em>. One piece written about this event was described as a \u201cmemory space\u201d by its composer. In its aftermath, the Last Night of the Proms removed <em>Fantasia on British Sea Songs</em> from their program. Another piece about this event opens with a violin imitating a phone left off the hook, and is scored for three string quartets plus tape. It was the subject of John Adams\u2019 <em>On The Transmigration Of Souls</em> and a Steve Reich piece which includes NORAD and FDNY recordings. For the point, in what tragedy did hijacked planes attack the Pentagon and World Trade Center?", "answer": "<b><u>9/11</u></b> [or the <b><u>September 11th</u> </b>attacks, or equivalent]  {III}", "metadata": "CW"}, {"question": "Scholars such as Wolfgang Mieder interpret the story of the Pied Piper of Hamelin as an allegory for the migration of Germans to this region. From 1711 to 1867, this region existed as a principality ruled by Habsburg imperial governors. Following the Battle of Mohacs (<b>pr. MOE-hotch</b>), the <em>voivode</em> of this region, John Zapolya, ascended to the throne. Though he ruled Wallachia, Vlad the Impaler was born in this historical region. This region's name is Latin for \u201cbeyond the woods.\u201d For the point, name this region of western Romania which, mainly due to a novel by Bram Stoker, conjures up images of vampires.", "answer": "<b><u>Transylvania</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "AG"}, {"question": "A member of this group at the time of his death was the gambler \"Buckey\" O'Neill. This group was supplied by the yachtsman Woodbury Kane, and members wore blue flannel shirts and polka-dot bandanas. This group was unofficially known as \"Wood's Weary Walkers,\" after first leader Leonard Wood. Members gave their leader a version of Remington's \"Bronco Buster\" at their farewell party. This group made a famous charge up Kettle Hill during the Battle of San Juan Hill. For the point, name this volunteer regiment led by Teddy Roosevelt during the Spanish-American War.", "answer": "<b><u>Rough Riders</u></b> [or <b><u>1st</u></b> United States <b><u>Volunteer Cavalry</u></b>]  {III}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "In Flanders, a group with this belief system known as Blood, Soil, Honour, and Loyalty, emerged in 2004. The Lansdowne Road Football Riot was caused by a group with this belief system, known as Combat 18. This ideology is possessed by Landser, a criminally-outlawed rock band. This ideology is often ascribed to Jobbik in Hungary and to the Golden Dawn party in Greece. The Verbotsgesetz 1947 law in Austria was violated by the National Democratic Party, a party with this ideology. Possessors of this ideology often air their thoughts on Stormfront. For the point, name this xenophobic, Holocaust-denying ideology that is resurging in Europe.", "answer": "neo-<b><u>Nazi</u></b>sm [or word forms; prompt on fascism or word forms; accept <b><u>white</u></b> <b><u>supremacy</u></b>; accept <b><u>white nationalism</u></b>; prompt on <b><u>anti-Semitism</u></b> or word forms]  {III}", "metadata": "AG"}, {"question": "This man easily defeated Ken Norton at the \"Caracas Caper.\"Norman Mailer claimed this athlete lost a match thanks to Angelo Dundee loosening the tightness of the ropes. This man's victory at the Sunshine Showdown in Jamaica was marked by Howard Cosell's call of \"Down goes Frazier! Down goes Frazier\"! He lost his championship in 1974 in a match where his opponent used the \"rope-a-dope\" strategy in Zaire. This man lost to Muhammad Ali at the \"Rumble in the Jungle.\" For the point, name this boxer who in 1994 became the oldest heavyweight boxing champion in history.", "answer": "George <b><u>Foreman</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "This man searched Fast Castle as part of a treasure hunt with Robert Logan. This man coined the phrase rabdology in a treatise of the same name, which describes devices he created to simplify arithmetic such as his promptuary. One of the devices this man created to simplify multiplication was inspired by lattice multiplication, and is a set of rods known as his \u201cbones.\u201d Henry Briggs developed a table for the function this man discovered, and in particular Briggs set those functions to use a base of 10. For the point, name this mathematician who discovered the logarithm.", "answer": "John <b><u>Napier</u></b> [or <b><u>Marvellous Merchiston</u>] </b> {III}", "metadata": "Ike"}, {"question": "An alternative to this measure was proposed by a president who had sent T. Butler King to bring a certain state into the union without it first going through the territorial phase. This legislation was opposed by the Nashville Convention. A speech given in support of it was known as the \u201cHigher Law\u201d speech. This \u201cOmnibus Bill\u201d established the territories of Utah and New Mexico, admitted California as a free state, and included a new and harsher Fugitive Slave Act. For the point, name this last compromise drafted by Henry Clay, named for a year.", "answer": "<b><u>Compromise of 1850</u></b> [prompt on <b><u>Omnibus Bill</u></b> before read; \u201cCompromise\u201d not needed after read]  {III}", "metadata": "SH"}, {"question": "An infantry commander at this battle, Adam Lewenhaupt, abandoned his supply train following his defeat at Lesnaya. After the would-be commander of this battle's losing side was shot in the foot, Gustaf Rehnskiold assumed command. The escape of this battle's losing side to the Ottoman-controlled Bender was followed by the Pruth River Campaign. Before this battle, the Cossack hetman Ivan Mazepa switched allegiances. This battle was a major defeat for a wounded Charles XII, who had earlier won the 1700 Battle of Narva. For the point, name this 1709 victory for Peter the Great during the Great Northern War.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Poltava</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "KG"}, {"question": "<em>Volkswagen sued National Lampoon over a joke about this event</em>. A man in this event was criticized for not using a telephone as he walked back to Lawrence Cottage. It occurred after a man left a party that was a reunion for the \"boiler-room girls.\" That man admitted that immediately after this event he thought of the \"awful curse\" hanging over his family. Mary Jo Kopechne died in this event, which damaged a Massachusetts politician's presidential aspirations. For the point, name this 1969 event in which Senator Ted Kennedy's female colleague was killed when he drove his car off a bridge.", "answer": "<b><u>Chappaquiddick</u></b> incident  {III}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "Margaret George wrote a historical novel called the Autobiography of [this ruler]. The 2009 Booker Prize was given to a novel set during this king's reign and named for a Wiltshire estate. The Globe Theatre burned to the ground after a cannon used in a play named for this character burned its thatched roofs. <em>Bring Up the Bodies</em> is a novel about an advisor to this king, who reigns in England in Hilary Mantel's <em>Wolf Hall.</em> One of this man\u2019s sons switches places with Tom Canty in Mark Twain\u2019s novel <em>The Prince and the Pauper</em>. For the point, name this king of England, who was advised by Thomas Cromwell and married six wives.", "answer": "<b><u>Henry VIII</u></b> [prompt on \u201cHenry\u201d]  {III}", "metadata": "Ike"}, {"question": "A ship named after this figure was the namesake of the flagship of a squadron that won the battle of the River Plate against the Admiral Graf Spee. This hero used a shield covered with seven cowhides to protect his half-brother Teucer. This hero was the namesake of the CIA operation that overthrew Mossadegh in Iran. In Book 14 of the <em>Iliad,</em> this hero threw a boulder that injured Hector. In the <em>Metamorphoses,</em> this hero lost a debate over Achilles\u2019s armor and then committed suicide. For the point, name this huge Greek hero of the Trojan war called \u201cGreater.\u201d", "answer": "Greater <b><u>Ajax</u></b> [or Telamonian <b><u>Ajax</u></b>; or <b><u>Aias</u></b>; do not accept \u201cLesser Ajax\u201d]  {III}", "metadata": "PL"}, {"question": "Following their defeat in an 1814-16 war, these people were incorporated into an opposing force through the Treaty of Sugauli. These people often came from the Gurung, Magar, or Chhetri ethnic groups. These people used curved knives called khukuri. Reginald Dyer brought a regiment of these people to Amritsar in 1919, where they killed nearly four hundred people. Joanna Lumley campaigned for the rights of these people, who were once barred from living in the United Kingdom despite their service in the British Army. For the point, name these steadfast soldiers from Nepal.", "answer": "<b><u>Gurkha</u></b>s [or <b><u>Gorkha</u></b>s; prompt on <b><u>Nepalese</u></b>]  {III}", "metadata": "KG"}, {"question": "The early years of this organization were known as the \u201cRainbow Era.\u201d This organization\u2019s president George Warrington once claimed it was on a \u201cglide path to self-sufficiency,\u201d and it was widely expected to shut down two years after assuming routes from twenty carriers in 1971. Its planned Gateway Project would build a new pair of tunnels underneath the Hudson River, and it was forced to truncate the <em>Sunset Limited</em> after Hurricane Katrina. Its most profitable route is the <em>Acela Express</em>, along the Northeast Corridor<em>.</em> For the point, what publicly-funded corporation provides intercity passenger rail service in the United States?", "answer": "<b><u>Amtrak</u></b> [or <b><u>National Railroad Passenger Corporation</u></b>]  {III}", "metadata": "CW"}, {"question": "During this battle, Scottish engineer Johannes Grant commanded counter-mining operations under the city walls. One commander in this battle created a slide of greased logs in order to transport ships overland past a chain in the water. During this battle, cannons designed by Orban helped damage the Theodosian Walls, which had stood for over 1000 years. Emperor Constantine XI was killed during this battle, a victory for Sultan Mehmed II. For the point, which 1453 event saw the Ottomans conquer the capital of the Byzantine Empire?", "answer": "Fall of <b><u>Constantinople</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "TR"}, {"question": "This action was supposed to have taken place at the same time as an attack on the enemy\u2019s right flank by \u201cAllegheny\u201d Johnson. During this event, the late William Pender\u2019s division was commanded by Isaac Trimble. This event began with a 170-cannon bombardment by Porter Alexander. Lewis Armistead was killed during this event after reaching the \u201ccopse of trees\u201d on Cemetery Ridge. This action reached the \u201chigh-water mark of the Confederacy,\u201d and took place the day after the fighting at Little Round Top. For the point, name this failed assault during the Battle of Gettysburg.", "answer": "<b><u>Pickett\u2019s Charge</u></b> [prompt on Battle of <b><u>Gettysburg</u></b> before mention]  {III}", "metadata": "SH"}, {"question": "One man with this surname ruled with the aid of Luckner Cambronne. A counterinsurgency force called the Leopards existed under a leader with this surname. Another man with this surname directed his country\u2019s anti-yaws campaign before organizing resistance to Paul Magloire. That man with this surname executed his aide Cl\u00e9ment Barbot, organized a security force called the Tontons Macoutes, and appropriated his country\u2019s voodoo for political purposes. For the point, name this Haitian ruling family whose members included \u201cPapa Doc\u201d and \u201cBaby Doc.\u201d", "answer": "<b><u>Duvalier</u></b>s  {III}", "metadata": "SH"}, {"question": "<em>After Hayreddin Barbarossa\u2019s defeat at Tunis, he sacked this island\u2019s capital of Mahon</em>. The 1756 Siege of Fort St. Philip captured this island, and shortly afterwards Admiral John Byng was hanged for having \u201cfailed to do his utmost\u201d to defend this island during the Seven Years\u2019 War. The Treaty of Utrecht ceded Gibraltar and this island \u201cin perpetuity\u201d to Britain, who used it as a naval base in the Western Mediterranean. The Treaty of Amiens permanently returned this island to Spain. For the point, name this Balearic Island, which is smaller than Majorca.", "answer": "<b><u>Minorca</u></b> [or <b><u>Menorca</u></b>]  {III}", "metadata": "PL"}, {"question": "This party was the subject of Rick Perlstein's 2001 book Before the Storm. This party nominated a presidential candidate who sued Ralph Ginzburg and <em>Fact</em> magazine for suggesting he was \"mentally unfit.\" The speech \"A Time for Choosing\" was given to support this party, whose nominee used the slogan \"In your heart, you know he's right\" and who claimed \"extremism in the defense of liberty is no vice.\" This party's candidate was implicitly attacked with the \"daisy ad\" depicting a nuclear explosion. For the point, name this political party that nominated Barry Goldwater for the presidency in 1964.", "answer": "<b><u>Republican</u></b> Party [or <b><u>G.O.P.</u></b>; or <b><u>Grand Old Party</u></b>]  {III}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "In the aftermath of this event, Getya Gelfman escaped execution due to her pregnancy. A group of revolutionaries responsible for this event were named \"those of the First of March\" after the date when it took place. During this event, Nikolai Rysakov's efforts were stymied by a bulletproof carriage gifted by Napoleon III. Upon stepping out of that carriage, this event's target was fatally wounded by Ignacy Hryniewiecki's bomb. This event, which delayed the creation of a Duma, was carried out by a group known as the People's Will. For the point, identify this 1881 event in which a tsar who emancipated the serfs was killed.", "answer": "<b><u>assassination</u></b> of <b><u>Alexander II</u></b> [accept equivalents for \u201cassassination\u201d]  {III}  <b>Extra Tossups</b>", "metadata": "KG"}, {"question": "<em>Opposition to this man increased significantly following a statement he made to James</em> <em>Creelman of Pearson's Magazine.</em> This man pushed for banning re-election of the president in his Plan of Tuxtepec. Manuel Gonzalez served a term as president after this man promised a \"no re-election\" campaign, only to take power again afterwards. Jose Limantour and Justo Sierra were among a group of confidantes to this man collectively known as the <em>Cientificos</em>. This man was opposed in the Plan of San Luis Potosi of Francisco Madero, who succeeded him. For the point, name this President who was deposed in the 1911 Mexican Revolution.", "answer": "Jose de la Cruz Porfirio <b><u>Diaz</u></b> Mori  {III}", "metadata": "JL"}, {"question": "<em>This man discussed hiding battle plans in sketches of butterflies in his book</em> My Adventures as a Spy. This man's soldiers planted fake landmines and avoided non-existent barbed wire, extending a siege to 217 days. This man held a rally at the Crystal Palace, where he was convinced to form a female counterpart to an organization he founded. This man first gained fame for holding out at the Siege of Mafeking, which inspired him to found a camp at Brownsea Island. After meeting this man, Juliette Gordon Low was inspired to found the Girl Scouts of  America.  For  the  point,  name  this  founder  of  the  British  Scout  Association.", "answer": "Robert <b><u>Baden-Powell</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "KG"}, {"question": "<em>This site\u2019s Stairway of Fountains runs parallel to its series of 16 fountains.</em> The discoverer of this site initially suggested that it was a sanctuary for the Aclla Cuna. Religious buildings at this site include the Temple of the Condor and the trapezoidal Temple of the Three Windows. Its main plaza includes the Intihuatana sundial, and this place is believed to have been an estate of Pachacuti. This site sits above the Urubamba River valley, and was discovered in 1911 by Hiram Bingham. For the point, name this \u201clost city of the Incas.\u201d", "answer": "<b><u>Machu Picchu</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "SH"}, {"question": "<em>A man with this surname led the U.S. Army into Utah shortly after the Mountain Meadows</em> <em>Massacre.</em> A man with this surname led forces at the Battle of Seven Pines and was succeeded by Robert E. Lee after he was struck in the chest. Another man with this surname was shot in the leg while fighting at the \"Peach Orchard.\" A man with this surname reinforced P.G.T. Beauregard at the Battle of First Bull Run and surrendered to William T. Sherman following the \"March to the Sea.\" For the point, give this surname shared by Confederate Generals Joseph and Albert Sidney, the latter of whom was killed at the Battle of Shiloh.", "answer": "<b><u>Johnston</u></b>  {III}", "metadata": "KG"}, {"question": "<em>As secretary of commerce, this man ended the 12-hour day in the steel industry.</em> President Calvin Coolidge appointed this man head of a special Mississippi Flood Committee. After World War I, this man served as head of the Commission for Relief in Belgium; his success in that position led Woodrow Wilson to appoint him head of the American Relief Administration, feeding victims of famine in the Soviet Union. This man was named secretary of commerce by Warren G. Harding. For the point, name this president at the start of the Great Depression.", "answer": "Herbert Clark <b><u>Hoover</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "SH"}], "bonuses": []}